Guide to the Rudolf Carnap Papers, 1904-2007 ASP.1974.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence and Diaries, 1908-1970; V.
  - Correspondence with Family, Friends, and Carnap's Diaries, 1908-1970; 1.
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1911-1919 (Box 25, Folder 71)
      - Diary, January-April 1916; 10.
      - Diary, May-September 1916; 11.
      - Diary, September-November 1916; 12.
      - Diary, November 1916-May 1917; 13.
      - Diary, May 1917; 14.
      - Diary, May-August 1917; 15.
      - Diary, October 1917-October 1918; 16.
      - Diary, October 1918-November 1919; 17.
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1922-1927 (Box 25, Folder 72)
      - Diary, September-December 1922; 1.
      - Diary, January 1923-January 1924; 2.
      - Diary, January-December 1924; 3.
      - Diary, January 1925-January 1926; 4.
      - Diary, January 1925-January 1926; 5.
      - Diary, January-June 1927; 6.
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1927-1931 (Box 25, Folder 73)
      - Diary, July-December 1927; 1.
      - Diary, December 1927-December 1928; 2.
      - Diary, December 1928-December 1929; 3.
      - Diary, December 1929-January 1931; 4.
      - Diary, January-December 1931; 5.
      - Later Notes, 1928-1930; 6.
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 74)
      - Diary, April 1969-December 1969; 1.
      - Diary, January 1970-August 1970; 2.
      - Diary (Families), 1965-1967; 3.
      - Diary (Financial), 1965-1967; 4.
      - Diary (Correspondence), 1935-1970; 5.
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1920-1935 (Box 25, Folder 75)
      - Diary, May-December 1920; 1.
      - Diary, April 1921-July 1922; 2.
      - Notecards from Diary, 1932-1935; 3.
      - Diary, December 1931-December 1932; 4.
      - Diary, January 1933-January 1934; 5.
      - Diary, January 1934-January 1935; 6.
      - Diary, January-December 1935; 7.
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1966-1968 (Box 25, Folder 76)
      - 1. Diary, January 1967-December, 1967
      - 2. Diary, December 1966-January 1967
      - 3. Diary, February 1967-June 1967
      - 4. Diary, July 1967-October 1967
      - 5. Diary, October 1967-January 1968
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1963-1965 (Box 25, Folder 77)
      - 1. Diary, January 1963-December 1963
      - 2. Diary, January-December 1964
      - 3. Diary, January 1964-December 1965
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1959-1962 (Box 25, Folder 78)
      - 1. Diary, March 1959-December 1959
      - 2. Diary, December 1959-December 1960
      - 3. Diary, December 1960-January 1962
      - 4. Diary, January-December 1962
    - Tagebuch [Diaries] (Item 1a), 1954-1956 (Box 25, Folder 79a)
    - Tagebuch [Diaries] (Item 1b), 1957-1959 (Box 25, Folder 79b)
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1952-1954 (Box 25, Folder 80)
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 81)
      - Diary, December 1943-December 1944; 1.
      - Diary, December 1944-December 1945; 2.
      - Diary, December 1945-December 1946; 3.
      - Diary, December 1946-December 1947; 4.
      - Diary, December 1947-December 1948; 5.
      - Diary, December 1948-January 1950; 6.
      - Diary, January-December 1950; 7.
      - Diary, December 1950-December 1951; 8.
      - Diary, December 1951-September 1952; 9.
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1935-1943 (Box 25, Folder 82)
      - Diary, December 1935-December 1936; 1.
      - Diary, December 1936-Dec. 1937; 2.
      - Diary, December 1937-December 1938; 3.
      - Diary, December 1938-December 1939; 4.
      - Diary, December 1939-December 1940; 5.
      - Diary, December 1940-December 1941; 6.
      - Diary, December 1941-December 1942; 7.
      - Diary, December 1942-December 1943; 8.
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1962-1965 (Box 25, Folder 83)
      - 1. Diary, 1962
      - 2. Diary, 1963
      - 3. Diary, 1964
      - 4. Diary, 1965
    - Tagebuch [Diaries], 1966-1970 (Box 25, Folder 84)
      - 1. Diary, 1966
      - 2. Diary, 1967
      - 3. Diary, 1968
      - 4. Diary, 1969
      - 5. Diary, 1970
    - Rudi und Elisabeth (Isabel) Chacha an Mutter Carnap, 1916-1923 (Box 25, Folder 85)
    - Von Mutter und Agnes, 1914-1915 (Box 25, Folder 86)
    - Von Mutter und Agnes, 1914-1917 (Box 25, Folder 87)
    - Elisabeth, 1930-1931 (Box 25, Folder 88)
    - Vortragsreise nach Kopenhagen und Schweden, Tagebuchseiten, November 1932 (Box 25, Folder 89)
    - Silvretta, Juli, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 90)
    - Reise S.F.-Chicago, Tagebuchseiten, 1944-1951 (Box 25, Folder 91)
    - Esperanto Kongresse Finland, Wien, Genf, Tagebuchseiten, 1922-1925 (Box 25, Folder 92)
    - Reisen nach Deutschland, Tagebuchseiten, 1964-1966 (Box 25, Folder 93)
      - 1. Diary, Reisen nach Deutschland, 1964
      - 2. Diary, Reisen nach Deutschland, 1964-1966
    - Griechenlandreise und Schweden, Tagebuchseiten, 1910-1913, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 94)
    - Garthe, Tagebuch der Marokkoreise, 1912 (Box 25, Folder 95)
    - Aufzeichnungen über Politische Stellungnahme, 1918 (Box 25, Folder 96)
    - Gelesene Bücher und Zeitungsausschnitt Anna Carnap, 1913-1917, 1934 (Box 25, Folder 97)
    - Bücher, die ich gelesen, 1909 (Box 25, Folder 98)
    - Tagebuch Mexico, Personen in Mexico, 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 99)
      - 1. Diary, Mexico, December 1969-January 1970
    - Postcards to Ina, 1927-1932 (Box 25, Folder 100)
    - Sera, Sonnwendbriefe, Friedenssonnwende: Sera Kreis Booklets, 1913-1919 (Box 25, Folder 101)
  - Correspondence Personal and Professional, A-Z, 1947-1970; 2.
    - Correspondence A, 1957-1961 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence B, 1957-1963 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence C, 1947-1962 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence D, 1954-1962 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence E, 1957-1958 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence F, 1947-1963 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence G, 1955-1963 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence H, 1954-1962 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence Jose Manuel Duarte de Jesus, 1959-1960 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence K, 1957-1961 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence L, 1949-1962 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence M, 1953-1962 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence N, 1958-1960 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence Seizo Ohe, 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence P, 1957-1962 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence R, 1955-1962 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence S, 1952-1963 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence T, 1956-1962 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence Vonessen, Irmela, 1957-1958 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence W, 1957-1963 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence Z, 1956-1962 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Current Correspondence A, 1963-1969 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Current Correspondence B, 1963-1970 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Current Correspondence B, C, 1963-1970 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Current Correspondence C, D, 1957-1969 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Current Correspondence E, 1963-1968 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Current Correspondence F, 1963-1970 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Current Correspondence G, 1964-1969 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Current Correspondence H, 1961-1969 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Current Correspondence I, J, 1961-1970 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Current Correspondence K, 1958-1970 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Current Correspondence L, 1956-1970 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Current Correspondence M, 1962-1970 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Current Correspondence N, 1956-1970 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Current Correspondence O, 1959-1969 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Current Correspondence P, Q, 1960-1970 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Current Correspondence R, S, 1961-1970 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Current Correspondence S, 1963-1970 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Current Correspondence T, 1961-1969 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Current Correspondence T, U, V, 1961-1969 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Current Correspondence W, 1959-1970 (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - Current Correspondence X, Y, Z, 1958-1969 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - International Colloquium on the Philosophy of Science, London 1965: Drafts and Correspondence, 1960-1967; 3.
    - Page Proofs of Carnap's "Inductive Logic and Intuition", 1967 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Drafts of Discussions and Comments by Various Authors for The Problem of Inductive Logic, Proceedings of the International Colloquium in the Philosophy of Science, London, 1965, Vol. II, North Holland Publ. Co., Amsterdam, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Drafts of Carnap's "Inductive Logic and Intuition, 1960-1967 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - International Colloquium on the Philosophy of Science, London, Conference Program, Notes, and Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Carnap's Comments on Discussion, Drafts, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - Discussion Remarks to Kyburg, Bar-Hillel, Salmon, Hintakka; and Correspondence with Lakatos, 1965-1966 (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence with Imre Lakatos, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Lakatos Ms. Draft "Logical Empiricism: A Logic of Justification without a Logic of Discovery?", 1967 (Box 27, Folder 50)
    - Popper Ms. Draft "Theories, Experience, and Probabilistic Intuitions, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - Popper Ms. Draft "Theories, Experience, and Probabilistic Intuitions, Previous Version (Box 27, Folder 52)
    - Mss. Drafts and Fragments by Bar-Hillel, Watkins, Carnap, Bunge, Hintikka, and Lakatos, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence with Publishers, 1926-1962; 4.
    - Addresses of Publishers (Box 27, Folder 54)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1937, 1958-1962 (Box 27, Folder 55)
    - Dover Publishing, Inc., 1958-1962 (Box 27, Folder 56)
    - Harvard University Press, 1957-1959 (Box 27, Folder 57)
    - Felix Meiner Verlagsbuchhandlung, 1926-1958 (Box 27, Folder 58)
    - Routledge and Kegan Paul Limited, 1954-1962 (Box 27, Folder 59)
    - Early Correspondence with Individuals and Institutions, 1908-1935; 5.
      - Ajdukiewicz, Kasimir, 1933-1934 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Bachmann, Friedrich, 1932-1935 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Bauch, Bruno, 1920 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Bavink, Bernhard, 1930-1934 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Becker, Albrecht, 1934-1935 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Behmann, Heinrich, 1930-1934 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Behmann, Heinrich, 1928-1929 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Burkamp, Wilhelm, 1927-1928 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Professional and Educational Documents and Certificates, 1910-1930 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Christiansen, Broder, 1922-1931 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - Christiansen, Broder: Prospekte (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Dingler, Hugo, 1920-1923 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Dubislav, Walter, 1926-1931 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Dürr, Karl, 1931 (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - Eklund, Hjalmar Magnus, 1929 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - Engel, F., 1921 (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - Erdélyi, Arthur, 1934 (Box 28, Folder 17)
      - Esperanto, U.E.A. Membership Cards, 1908-1922 (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - Esperanto, U.E.A. Correspondence, 1915, 1925-1926 (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - Kaufmann, Felix, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Kaufmann, Felix, 1934 (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - Kaufmann, Felix, 1933 (Box 28, Folder 22)
      - Kaufmann, Felix, 1932 (Box 28, Folder 23)
      - Kaufmann, Felix, 1930-1931 (Box 28, Folder 24)
      - Kaufmann, Felix, 1927-1929 (Box 28, Folder 25)
      - Kaufmann, Felix, 1926-1932 (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - Klatt, Fritz (Box 28, Folder 27)
      - Kraus, Oskar, 1928-1934 (Box 28, Folder 28)
      - Worsley, S.J., 1934 (Box 28, Folder 29)
      - Verein Ernst Mach, 1929-1931 (Box 28, Folder 30)
      - Menger, Karl, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Merten, Bernhard, 1929-1933 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Schmidt, Heinrich: Monistenbund, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Morris, Charles, 1933-1935 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Nagel, Ernest, 1934-1935 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Natkin, M., 1928 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Neider, Heinz, 1933-1935 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Neumann, Johann von, 1931 (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Neurath, Otto, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Neurath, Otto, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - Neurath, Otto, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - Neurath, Otto, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - Neurath, Otto, 1931 (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - Neurath, Otto, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - Neurath, Otto, 1929 (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - Neurath, Otto, 1923-1928 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Neurath, Otto, 1930-1934 (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - Neurath, Otto: Diskussion Boltzmanngasse, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - Neurath, Otto, 1926 and 1931 (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - Neurath, Olga, 1931-1935 (Box 29, Folder 20)
      - Nohl, Hermann, 1921- 1933 (Box 29, Folder 21)
      - Philosophischer Kongress, Prag, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 22)
      - Pieper, Josef, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 23)
      - Rougier, Louis, 1932-1935 (Box 29, Folder 24)
      - Sauer, Friedrich, 1929-1930 (Box 29, Folder 25)
      - Schiller, F.-C. S., 1934 (Box 29, Folder 26)
      - Schlick, Moritz, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 27)
      - Schlick, Moritz, 1933-1934 (Box 29, Folder 28)
      - Schlick, Moritz, 1931-1932 (Box 29, Folder 29)
      - Schlick, Moritz, 1927-1930 (Box 29, Folder 30)
      - Schlick, Moritz, 1927 (Box 29, Folder 31)
      - Schlick, Moritz, 1922-1927 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Springer Verlag, 1937, 1954-1962 (Box 29, Folder 60)
    - John Wily & Son, Inc., Princeton University Press, McGraw-Hill, 1949-1962 (Box 29, Folder 61)
    - The Macmillan Co., 1956-1957 (Box 29, Folder 62)
- Induction and Probability, 1933-1958, VI.
  This series contains drafts documenting Carnap's research in induction and probability, mainly in the 1940s and early 1950s for various publications, among them The Continuum of Inductive Methods (1952) and The Logical Foundations of Probability (1950). Included are also manuscripts for apparently unpublished projects.
  - On "Continuum"(and for "Continuum"), 1951 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Mixed Things, 1953-1953 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Open Families, 1954 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - One Family, without λ, (Items 1-4), 1954 (Box 78, Folder 4a)
  - One Family, without λ, (Items 5-12), 1954 (Box 78, Folder 4b)
  - One Family, without λ, (Items 13-17), 1954 (Box 78, Folder 4c)
  - Two Families, October 1952-February 1953 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Two Families, with Kemeny, 1952-1953 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Two Families, February, 1953 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Two Families, May-June 1953 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Probability, Vol. II. Appendix A, 1950 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Plan and Contents for: "Probability and Induction, ", 1943-1950 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - One Family, without λ, (Items 1-3), 1958 (Box 78, Folder 11a)
  - One Family, without λ, (Items 4-6), 1958 (Box 78, Folder 11b)
  - One Family, without λ, (Item 7), 1958 (Box 78, Folder 11c)
  - One Family, without λ, (Items 8-9), 1958 (Box 78, Folder 11d)
  - One Family, without λ, (Item 10), 1958 (Box 78, Folder 11e)
  - One Family, without λ, (Item 11), 1958 (Box 78, Folder 11f)
  - Remarks on Continuum, perhaps for Vol. II, 1950-1951 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Über Daniel Bernoulli: Probability in Economics, 1948 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Principle of Indifference, Chapter XI, 1947 (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - The Adequacy of N*: Skelett für Chapter 10, Band II, 1945-1950 (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - The Straight Rule, Chapter XII, (Items 1-4), 1947-1949 (Box 78, Folder 16a)
  - The Straight Rule, Chapter XII, (Items 5-9), 1947-1949 (Box 78, Folder 16b)
  - Skelett Square Error, Chapter XIII für Ms Cont., (Items 1-2), 1948-1949 (Box 78, Folder 17a)
  - Skelett Square Error, Chapter XIII für Ms Cont., (Items 3-5), 1948-1949 (Box 78, Folder 17b)
  - The S.R. leads to the Nothing-New Principle, Chapter XII, (Item 1), 1948 (Box 78, Folder 18a)
  - The S.R. leads to the Nothing-New Principle, Chapter XII, (Items 2-3), 1948 (Box 78, Folder 18b)
  - Prüfung von induktiven Methoden: Skelett Chapter XIII, (Items 1-5), 1949 (Box 78, Folder 19a)
  - Prüfung von induktiven Methoden: Skelett Chapter XIII, (Items 6-11), 1949 (Box 78, Folder 19b)
  - Abhängigkeit von N* vom Sprachsystem, (Items 1-2), 1945 (Box 78, Folder 20a)
  - Abhängigkeit von N* vom Sprachsystem, (Item 3), 1945 (Box 78, Folder 20b)
  - Skeleton Probability, (Item 1), 1943-1950 (Box 78, Folder 21a)
  - Skeleton Probability, (Items 2-3), 1943-1950 (Box 78, Folder 21b)
  - Skeleton Probability: Direkter Schluß, Voraussageschluß und anderes über N*, (Items 1-3), 1943-1946 (Box 78, Folder 22a)
  - Skeleton Probability: Direkter Schluß, Voraussageschluß und anderes über N*, (Items 4-6), 1943-1946 (Box 78, Folder 22b)
  - Skeleton Probability, (Items 1-2), 1943-1944 (Box 78, Folder 23a)
  - Skeleton Probability, (Items 3-5), 1943-1944 (Box 78, Folder 23b)
  - Andere N mit Ähnlichkeit der Q's, (Items 1-2), 1943 (Box 78, Folder 24a)
  - Andere N mit Ähnlichkeit der Q's, (Item 3), 1943 (Box 78, Folder 24b)
  - Uniformity of Nature, als Voraussetzung der Induktion, 1942-1947 (Box 78, Folder 25)
  - D II, II, IV, 1943 (Box 78, Folder 26)
  - Vergleich durch Wetten, (Items 1-3), 1944-1946 (Box 78, Folder 27a)
  - Vergleich durch Wetten, (Items 4-5), 1944-1946 (Box 78, Folder 27b)
  - Vergleich durch Wetten, (Items 6-10), 1944-1946 (Box 78, Folder 27c)
  - Vergleich von Wetten (Neues), (Items 1-3), 1947-1949 (Box 79, Folder 1a)
  - Vergleich von Wetten (Neues), (Items 4-6), 1947-1949 (Box 79, Folder 1b)
  - Vergleich von Wetten (Neues), (Items 7-9), 1947-1949 (Box 79, Folder 1c)
  - Vergleich von Wetten (Neues), (Items 10-12), 1947-1949 (Box 79, Folder 1d)
  - Wettbilanz D VII (mit und Ф, λ), (Items 1-2), 1948 (Box 79, Folder 2a)
  - Wettbilanz D VII (mit und Ф, λ), (Items 3-6), 1948 (Box 79, Folder 2b)
  - D VIII: Estimate of Uniformity of the Universe, 1949 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - E I-V, geordneter Bereich, (Items 1-2), 1943-1948 (Box 79, Folder 4a)
  - E I-V, geordneter Bereich, (Items 3-6), 1943-1948 (Box 79, Folder 4b)
  - E VI-VIII, Prob. geordneter Bereich, Randomness, 1947 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - E IX-X, Prob. geordneter Bereich, (Items 1-2), 1947-1951 (Box 79, Folder 6a)
  - E IX-X, Prob. geordneter Bereich, (Item 3), 1947-1951 (Box 79, Folder 6b)
  - E IX-X, Prob. geordneter Bereich, (Items 4-5), 1947-1951 (Box 79, Folder 6c)
  - E XII-XIII, neue Methode für geordneten Bereich, (Items 1-3), 1951 (Box 79, Folder 7a)
  - E XII-XIII, neue Methode für geordneten Bereich, (Items 4-6), 1951 (Box 79, Folder 7b)
  - E XII-XIII, neue Methode für geordneten Bereich, (Items 7-8), 1951 (Box 79, Folder 7c)
  - Skel. Prob. (über N*, 2. Art von Gesetzen, Instanz Konfirmation), (Item 1), 1943-1944 (Box 79, Folder 8a)
  - Skel. Prob. (über N*, 2. Art von Gesetzen, Instanz Konfirmation), (Items 2-3), 1943-1944 (Box 79, Folder 8b)
  - Skel. Prob. (über N*, 2. Art von Gesetzen, Instanz Konfirmation), (Items 4-5), 1943-1944 (Box 79, Folder 8c)
  - Skel. Prob. (über N*, 2. Art von Gesetzen, Instanz Konfirmation), (Item 6), 1943-1944 (Box 79, Folder 8d)
  - Skel. Prob. (über N*, 2. Art von Gesetzen, Instanz Konfirmation), (Items 7-9), 1943-1944 (Box 79, Folder 8e)
  - Skel. Prob. (über N*, Variety of Instances), 1943-1944 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - E, XIV: Fitting, (Items 1-3), 1951 (Box 79, Folder 10a)
  - E, XIV: Fitting, (Items 4-6), 1951 (Box 79, Folder 10b)
  - E, XIV: Fitting, (Items 7-9), 1951 (Box 79, Folder 10c)
  - E, XV: Randomness und χ2, 1950-1951 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - A, vom Febr. – März 1941 (meist überholt) (Items 1-4) (Box 79, Folder 12a)
  - A, vom Febr. – März 1941 (meist überholt) (Items 5-9) (Box 79, Folder 12b)
  - Neue Darstellung unserer Auffassung von N, vom April 1941 (und 1943) I-VIII, (Items 1-3), 1941-1943 (Box 79, Folder 13a)
  - Neue Darstellung unserer Auffassung von N, vom April 1941 (und 1943) I-VIII, (Items 4-5), 1941-1943 (Box 79, Folder 13b)
  - B, April 1941, IX-XVII, (Items 1-2), 1937-1943 (Box 79, Folder 14a)
  - B, April 1941, IX-XVII, (Items 3-6), 1937-1943 (Box 79, Folder 14b)
  - B, April 1941, IX-XVII, (Item 7), 1937-1943 (Box 79, Folder 14c)
  - B, April 1941, IX-XVII, (Items 8-9), 1937-1943 (Box 79, Folder 14d)
  - B, vom April 1941 (und 1943 –XVIII), (Items 1-2), 1942-1944 (Box 79, Folder 15a)
  - B, vom April 1941 (und 1943 –XVIII), (Items 3-5), 1942-1944 (Box 79, Folder 15b)
  - C, Topologiebegriff (1942), (Items 1-2), 1942-1944 (Box 79, Folder 16a)
  - C, Topologiebegriff (1942), (Items 3-5), 1942-1944 (Box 79, Folder 16b)
  - Correspondence with Prof. J. Doob: Über mengentheoretische Wahrscheinlichkeit, 1939 (Box 79, Folder 17)
  - Über Wahrheit, Wahrscheinlichkeit, dc: Truth, Verfication, für Diskussion mit Reichenbach, Paris, 1937-1941 (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - Vortrag Behmann; Harvard: D. Williams, 1933 and 1941 (Box 79, Folder 19)
  - Gewichtslogik, 1938-1941 (Box 79, Folder 20)
  - Konfirmationgrad, Positivismus, Physikalismus, 1941 (Box 79, Folder 21)
  - Diskussion über Semantik, mit Beitrag von anderen, (vielleicht Band V?), 1942 (Box 79, Folder 22)
  - Standard Word Language (vielleicht Band VI?), 1942 (Box 79, Folder 23)
  - Gewicht eines N, 1941 (Box 79, Folder 24)
  - JI, N für Straight Rule, 1944-1948 (Box 79, Folder 25)
  - G, N als "Best Estimate", 1945-1946 (Box 79, Folder 26)
  - H, Forderung für N; λ –Parameter, 1944-1949 (Box 79, Folder 27)
  - Ia, andere N, 1946-49-51 (Unabhängigkeit von n mit Ähnlichkeit der Q's als Funktion von Ni2), (Items 1-3), 1946-1949 (Box 79, Folder 28a)
  - Ia, andere N, 1946-49-51 (Unabhängigkeit von n mit Ähnlichkeit der Q's als Funktion von Ni2), (Items 4-7), 1946-1949 (Box 79, Folder 28b)
  - I, b,c: Andere N, mit Berücksichtigung der Ähnlichkeit der Qs, 1946-1951 (Box 79, Folder 29)
  - Fallacy of Reversed Estimation, J II, 1946-1948 (Box 79, Folder 30)
  - Sampling Distribution, (Items 1-3), 1948-1949 (Box 79, Folder 31a)
  - Sampling Distribution, (Items 4-5), 1948-1949 (Box 79, Folder 31b)
  - Sampling Distribution, (Items 6-9), 1948-1949 (Box 79, Folder 31c)
  - M III MO2 für NN, 1948-1949 (Box 79, Folder 32)
  - MIV λ ∆, 1948-1949 (Box 79, Folder 33)
  - K, Induktionsmaschine, 1935, 1946-1947 (Box 79, Folder 34)
  - J III, NN- Ben Akiba, (Items 1-3), 1946-1949 (Box 79, Folder 35a)
  - J III, NN- Ben Akiba, (Items 4-7), 1946-1949 (Box 79, Folder 35b)
  - J III, NN- Ben Akiba, (Items 8-10), 1946-1949 (Box 79, Folder 35c)
  - J III, NN- Ben Akiba, (Items 11-13), 1946-1949 (Box 79, Folder 35d)
  - J III, NN- Ben Akiba, (Items 14-17), 1946-1949 (Box 79, Folder 35e)
  - J III, NN- Ben Akiba, (Items 18-20), 1946-1949 (Box 79, Folder 35f)
  - N, Wald's Decision Function (und Maximal-Regel), 1948 and 1951 (Box 79, Folder 36)
  - Q, Induktive Logik für quantitative Sprache, (Items 1-3), März 1951, 1947 and 1951 (Box 79, Folder 37a)
  - Q, Induktive Logik für quantitative Sprache, (Items 4-12), März 1951, 1947 and 1951 (Box 79, Folder 37b)
  - M V, Schrittweise Verbesserung von λΔ und Schätzung, (Items 1-4), 1948-1950 (Box 79, Folder 38a)
  - M V, Schrittweise Verbesserung von λΔ und Schätzung, (Items 5-8), 1948-1950 (Box 79, Folder 38b)
- Notes and Correspondence of Later Years and Manuscripts on Entropy, 1954-1970; VII.
  The first part of the series (subseries 1) contains notes and correspondence that accumulated during Carnap's last years. The second part (subseries 2) includes manuscript drafts on the concept of "entropy," which were authored in the early to mid 1950s. In these drafts, Carnap developed the abstract concept of entropy for use in inductive logic.
  - Notes and Correspondence of the Later Years, 1.
    - Miscellaneous Recent Notes and Correspondence, 1970 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Letters to be Written (Correspondence until 1969), 1957-1969 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Christmas Cards, 1967 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Notes and Letters (Odds and Ends), 1969 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Notes and Correspondence, 1969 and 1970 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - For Typing (Notes for Myself), 1967-1968 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Department of Philosophy UCLA, 1963-1970 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Deutscher Rundbrief, 1968 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Carnap Prize Essay Contest, 1969 (Box 80, Folder 9)